## DUMISANI LESLEY ZULU

Kamwala South, Lusaka · +260 978 646 664 **Dumisanilesleyzulu@gmail.com** 

Enthusiastic Information Technology personnel and self-taught data analyst with 2+ years of experience as an IT Officer. I have worked in different sectors and have gained valuable skills from my experiences and am eager to contribute to team success through hard work, attention to detail and excellent organizational skills. I am eager to learn new things every day and will always keep myself updated on the latest trends so that I can provide the best possible services to my clients.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

### **SEPTEMBER 2022 – PRESENT**

### INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY OFFICER

### SUPAMOTO (EMERGING COOKING SOLUTIONS)

- Configured and implemented IT initiatives to produce measurable business value.
- Incorporated technology guidelines, controls, processes, and solutions to mitigate business risks.
- Analyzed existing systems and databases and recommended enhancements to solve business needs.
- Collaborated closely with the fintech department to set up ticketing systems and various data analysis and visualization software's like power BI and Tableau.
- Network management, configuration, and monitoring
- Performed maintenance tasks on PCs, networks, and mobile devices.
- Configured systems according to prescribed software and hardware frameworks.
- Network Documentation and IT inventory management
- Used diagnostic tools to identify hardware failures and replace non-functional components.

## NOVEMBER 2020 - FEBRUARY 2021 IT SUPPORT INTERN CHETE FM

• Determined hardware and network system issues using proactive troubleshooting techniques.

- Responded to faults in both LAN and WAN networks to rapidly restore connectivity and prevent unnecessary downtimes.
- Set up and configured system hardware and software applications.
- Installed and configured network devices such as routers and wireless APs
- Provided Tier 1 IT support to non-technical internal users through desk side support services.
- Monitored systems in operation and input commands to troubleshoot areas.

## MARCH 2019 - MARCH 2020 SOFTWARE DEVELOPER INTERN (FRONT-END) ZED TUTORS ONLINE SERVICES LIMITED

- Worked in Agile-driven environment to effectively maintain project timelines and utilize available resources.
- Designed and updated layouts to meet usability and performance requirements.
- Developed designs to meet specific requirements such as quick-loading sites with layouts.
- Collaborated with in-house web designers to create sleek and innovative UI design.
- Coded websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and jQuery languages.
- Oversaw back-end development using PHP to maintain website integrity, security, and efficiency.
- Discussed site and app requirements with clients to produce actionable development plans and budgets.
- Collaborated with graphic design personnel to integrate images as basic site components.

### **EDUCATION**

# JANUARY 2018 - DECEMBER 2021 BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

ZAMBIA ICT COLLEGE

- Member of Itech Club
- Graduated with a Merit with a GPA of 3.5
- Graduated in the top 5 of my Class

JANUARY 2011 - NOVEMBER 2013 GRADE 12 CERTIFICATE LUBUTO HIGH SCHOOL

### **SKILLS**

- Hardware and Software troubleshooting,
- Network Infrastructure Support
- Data Communications
- Microsoft Office

- Data Visualization
- Computer Programming
- Information Security
- Data Exploration
- Data Cleaning

### **TOOLS AND SOFTWARES**

- Excel
- Python
- Power BI
- SQL
- Tableau

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Introduction to Cyber Security Cisco Networking Academy
- Network Security Associate 1&2 Fortinet
- Introduction to Business Intelligence Corporate Finance Institute
- Responsive Web Design Fundamentals Udacity
- Python Essentials 1 Cisco
- Networking Foundations: Networking Basics LinkedIn
- Information Technology (IT) and Cloud Fundamentals IBM Skills Network

### **REFERENCES**

#### 1. Mosho Malwemba

Information Technology Manager Supamoto +260 956 342039 mosho@supamoto.global

### 2. Kalenga Chambatu

Director of Operations Chete FM chetefm@gmail.com +260 967 653 964

### 3. David Nsai

Chief Technology Officer Zedtutors Online Services Limited nsaidave@gmail.com +260 974 532 915